<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Atharva Pandey</title>
    <link>https://atharvapandey.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Atharva Pandey</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright ©</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2024 18:30:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://atharvapandey.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Rust Ultimate: The Ultimate Rust Cheatsheet You&#39;ll Ever Need</title>
      <link>https://atharvapandey.com/post/rust-ultimate-the-ultimate-rust-cheatsheet-youll-ever-need/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2024 18:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://atharvapandey.com/post/rust-ultimate-the-ultimate-rust-cheatsheet-youll-ever-need/</guid>
      <description>Whether you&amp;rsquo;re a seasoned developer juggling multiple programming languages or a newcomer to Rust, it&amp;rsquo;s not uncommon to hit a roadblock trying to recall specific syntax or optimize your code with Rust&amp;rsquo;s powerful features. This comprehensive Rust cheatsheet is designed to be your go-to reference, enabling you to harness Rust&amp;rsquo;s capabilities fully without getting slowed down by syntax uncertainties.&#xA;Vector &amp;amp; LinkedList Operations Rust&amp;rsquo;s Vec&amp;lt;T&amp;gt; and LinkedList&amp;lt;T&amp;gt; are versatile for handling collections.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rust in Finance: Building a Scalable High-Frequency Trading Platform from Scratch</title>
      <link>https://atharvapandey.com/post/rust-in-finance-building-a-scalable-high-frequency-trading-platform-from-scratch.md/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2024 18:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://atharvapandey.com/post/rust-in-finance-building-a-scalable-high-frequency-trading-platform-from-scratch.md/</guid>
      <description>As I ventured deeper into the Rust ecosystem, I set my sights on a project that would not only challenge my technical acumen but also push the boundaries of software architecture — a high-frequency trading (HFT) platform. In the high-stakes world of high-frequency trading (HFT), where milliseconds can mean millions, the quest for the ultimate trading platform is relentless. With its relentless demand for speed, low latency and reliability, served as the perfect proving ground for my exploration into Rust’s capabilities and the architectural paradigms that would best harness them.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://atharvapandey.com/readme/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://atharvapandey.com/readme/</guid>
      <description>Atharva Pandey: Blockchain &amp;amp; Backend Developer 👋 I&amp;rsquo;m Atharva Pandey, a dynamic technology leader specializing in blockchain and backend development. With a proven track record in leading diverse teams and projects, I&amp;rsquo;ve been instrumental in delivering innovative solutions in the blockchain space, leveraging my skills as a Generalist and Polyglot.&#xA;🚀 Professional Journey As the CTO of Adguin, I spearheaded the creation of an NFT-based advertising platform, designing scalable, robust solutions from scratch.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
